<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://www.harisqazi.com/blog</id>
    <title>Portfolio Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.harisqazi.com/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Portfolio Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://www.harisqazi.com/img/HQ-Logo-Dark.png</icon>
    <rights>Copyright © 2024 Facebook, Inc.</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Initial Blog Post]]></title>
        <id>https://www.harisqazi.com/blog/initial-blog-post</id>
        <link href="https://www.harisqazi.com/blog/initial-blog-post"/>
        <updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have been meaning to switch to an open source static site generator for some time now. I have some time-intensive work coming up, so I wanted to knock this out before then. It was a fun experience and gave me the ability to have more control over the front-end of my website. In addition, it gave me a chance to leave GitBook in both format and in infrastructure. My new blog is hosted on Codeberg pages, the non-profit based out of Berlin, Germany. I do plan to have a backup on Cloudflare Pages as well, just in case of Codeberg downtimes. I am also using them as a primary git repository as well. GitHub is owned by Microsoft, and I just wanted to get out of the "Big Tech" ecosystem.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been meaning to switch to an open source static site generator for some time now. I have some time-intensive work coming up, so I wanted to knock this out before then. It was a fun experience and gave me the ability to have more control over the front-end of my website. In addition, it gave me a chance to leave GitBook in both format and in infrastructure. My new blog is hosted on Codeberg pages, the non-profit based out of Berlin, Germany. I do plan to have a backup on Cloudflare Pages as well, just in case of Codeberg downtimes. I am also using them as a primary git repository as well. GitHub is owned by Microsoft, and I just wanted to get out of the "Big Tech" ecosystem.</p>
<p>I now have a RSS feed. That can be found on <a href="https://www.harisqazi.com/blog/rss.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.harisqazi.com/blog/rss.xml</a>. After watching others (Jeff Geerling, crankysec, etc.) use RSS, I felt like I needed one for my work as well. I'll most likely be posting blogs as summaries or some key takeaways from the work I have in the documentation section.</p>
<p>I now also have a privacy policy. This was partially inspired by Michael Bazzell's IntelTechniques site. I wanted to be clear what I was doing with the end users' data - nothing. I think having a privacy policy makes it clear what your intentions are, but also allows for a form of checks and balances. I tell you I don't have access to your data. In return, since the source code is available publicly (<a href="https://codeberg.org/harisfromcyber/pages/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://codeberg.org/harisfromcyber/pages/</a>), you can hold me up to that.</p>
<p>I previously also had multiple licenses on the portfolio: one for the code, and one for the content. All of it is now under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International license. It allows you to share the content, even commercially, but attribution must be given. I spend days on my work, and would like to get credit if you were to use my work. I try my best to cite others in all my work as well. I feel like that is how the open-source world should be: give credit where it is due.</p>
<p>That is pretty much a summary of the big changes. I did a bit of housekeeping and removed all of my write-ups.</p>
<p>See you in the next one!</p>
<p>- Haris</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Haris Qazi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>